<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="/tum_info/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/tum_info/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-09-04T14:36:37+00:00</updated><id>/tum_info/feed.xml</id><title type="html">TUM Info</title><subtitle>A bunch of useful information I&apos;ve collected while studying at the Technical University of Munich.</subtitle><author><name>Mykola Morozov</name><email>mcmikecreations@gmail.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">Fixed exam statistics calculations!</title><link href="/tum_info/2024/09/04/maths.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fixed exam statistics calculations!" /><published>2024-09-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/tum_info/2024/09/04/maths</id><content type="html" xml:base="/tum_info/2024/09/04/maths.html"><![CDATA[<p>Happy autumn/fall to everyone!</p>

<p>One of the long-standing issues on GitHub for this website was having wrong formulas for exam statistics.
The system worked in two passes: a crude Liquid implementation for initial data and for browsers with disabled JavaScript
and a JavaScript implementation based on D3 that updates the fields when all of the statistics load. This meant I needed to
update both pieces of code every time I changed something, which brought many bugs to the table. Finally, I decided to ditch
the JavaScript implementation completely and focus only on Liquid. This should fix statistics both in the list and on the pages.</p>

<p>In other news, I added some new courses, updated the AweTUM page, and updated the CI/CD GitHub Actions pipeline.
Also, changed some titles around to improve Google Ranking (I still don’t use Google Analytics to avoid having tracking cookies).</p>

<p>If you want to support the website by contributing your own grades, check out <a href="https://mcmikecreations.github.io/tum_info/readme/#course-exam-statistics">the tutorial I wrote</a>. I’m looking forward to your submissions!</p>]]></content><author><name>Mykola Morozov</name><email>mcmikecreations@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Happy autumn/fall to everyone!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Added Aamin’s courses!</title><link href="/tum_info/2024/05/13/aamin.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Added Aamin’s courses!" /><published>2024-05-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-05-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/tum_info/2024/05/13/aamin</id><content type="html" xml:base="/tum_info/2024/05/13/aamin.html"><![CDATA[<p>Jolly spring to everyone!</p>

<p>Completely by accident I came across a link to <a href="https://stats.aamin.dev/">Aamin’s website</a> with grade reports from me and others. In the spirit of making a single full data source for grade reports, I have merged the grades from this website into TUM Info. Thanks to the CI/CD scripts that I wrote, the process wasn’t as painful as it was last few times, so now the list of courses, schools and the API endpoints are all up-to-date.</p>

<p>In other news, <a href="https://stats.aamin.dev/">Aamin’s website</a> had a more accurate representation of B/N pass/fail grades without a numeric value, so I took the chance to update the TUM Info dataset to handle it properly too.</p>

<p>In case you stumble on this message and want to contribute your own grades, check out <a href="https://mcmikecreations.github.io/tum_info/readme/#course-exam-statistics">the tutorial I wrote</a>. It would be amazing if you could help out!</p>]]></content><author><name>Mykola Morozov</name><email>mcmikecreations@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jolly spring to everyone!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Fixed departments and charts!</title><link href="/tum_info/2024/05/03/departments.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fixed departments and charts!" /><published>2024-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/tum_info/2024/05/03/departments</id><content type="html" xml:base="/tum_info/2024/05/03/departments.html"><![CDATA[<p>The executive board of Shijiazhuang Donghua Jinlong Chemical Co., LTD welcomes you.</p>

<p>As new students submit their grade reports to the website (and you should submit too), I’ve come across some issues that needed fixing.</p>

<p>First, I haven’t noticed <a href="https://mcmikecreations.github.io/tum_info/courses/CIT/MA8003/2019WS-endterm">a course which all people failed (5.0 X)</a> messing up my code to get average grades for quite a while. Now this has been fixed, and the chart proudly shows a 100% fail rate. The data source for this course is probably wrong, but it was a useful entry for edge case testing, so I’ll keep it unless someone has a better data point.</p>

<p>Second, a lot of professors started moving their courses into the school-based numbering system. This means that codes like <a href="https://mcmikecreations.github.io/tum_info/courses/CIT/CIT4230004/2023SS-endterm">CIT</a> and <a href="https://mcmikecreations.github.io/tum_info/courses/MGT/MGT001299/2023WS-endterm">MGT</a> are now valid numbering prefixes. The website needed an update to take this into account. For now, I don’t have time to make a mapping between old and new course codes, so you are <a href="https://github.com/mcmikecreations/tum_info/issues/180">welcome to contribute</a>!</p>

<p>As usual, I encourage people to send their new grade reports to the website. I do get a few submissions here and there, but it would be great to scale things up.</p>]]></content><author><name>Mykola Morozov</name><email>mcmikecreations@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The executive board of Shijiazhuang Donghua Jinlong Chemical Co., LTD welcomes you.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Added course reviews!</title><link href="/tum_info/2023/11/05/reviews.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Added course reviews!" /><published>2023-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/tum_info/2023/11/05/reviews</id><content type="html" xml:base="/tum_info/2023/11/05/reviews.html"><![CDATA[<p>Hello, Internet! Welcome to TUM Info.</p>

<p>A lot of students were complaining that grade reports are good, but don’t offer feedback from actual students taking the course. This has changed! On the new design, you can click on a course on the courses or schools page, which will send you to a page with all reviews. For example, <a href="https://mcmikecreations.github.io/tum_info/reviews/CIT/IN2064">Machine Learning</a>. The reviews are taken from the numerous chats created for study programs and specific courses.</p>

<p>If you have some free time, we are looking for volunteers to go through chat history and add it to the website. Contact us through the means listed <a href="https://github.com/mcmikecreations/tum_info/blob/87cd920fcb143dc31fa92d7e85c2fd9f1253ee73/scripts/course_glob_ui.py#L175">here</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name>Mykola Morozov</name><email>mcmikecreations@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello, Internet! Welcome to TUM Info.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Released the API!</title><link href="/tum_info/2023/09/10/api.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Released the API!" /><published>2023-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/tum_info/2023/09/10/api</id><content type="html" xml:base="/tum_info/2023/09/10/api.html"><![CDATA[<p>Top of the morning to you ladies! You asked and I delivered.</p>

<p>An EPIC new website addition to all you thirsty developers is the public API. A short description for it
can be found on the <a href="https://mcmikecreations.github.io/tum_info/readme/">ReadMe page</a>. But in summary,
I added a <a href="https://mcmikecreations.github.io/tum_info/api/description">Description page</a> with documentation
for every available endpoint and a <a href="https://mcmikecreations.github.io/tum_info/api/playground">Playground page</a>
where you can test out your own code. All course and school data on the website is available in the API,
so you can write your custom scripts or programs referencing it.</p>

<p>And another call to the website visitors. As the semester is over, don’t hesitate to contribute your grade distributions
to the website.</p>]]></content><author><name>Mykola Morozov</name><email>mcmikecreations@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Top of the morning to you ladies! You asked and I delivered.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Added AweTUM!</title><link href="/tum_info/2023/09/08/awetum.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Added AweTUM!" /><published>2023-09-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-09-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/tum_info/2023/09/08/awetum</id><content type="html" xml:base="/tum_info/2023/09/08/awetum.html"><![CDATA[<p>A beautiful day out here in Bavaria. And an exciting one, where a new major update came to the website!</p>

<p>First, I’ve added a new page to the website, <a href="https://mcmikecreations.github.io/tum_info/awetum/">AweTUM</a>,
featuring links to useful study resources and hobby projects of TUM students. If you have anything to add,
just PM/DM me the link with a short description. I hope to make the website a central point for useful
unofficial TUM-related stuff, so any help from you is highly welcome.</p>

<p>Second, I reworked the apps to accept unknown schools, departments and course formats.
This means you can safely ask your friends from Management, Architecture or Biology to contribute their grades!</p>

<p>Don’t forget that as the grades for the 2023SS have rolled out, you can contribute them here!
For that, check out the instructions in the <a href="https://mcmikecreations.github.io/tum_info/readme/">ReadMe</a>.
Stay toasty!</p>]]></content><author><name>Mykola Morozov</name><email>mcmikecreations@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A beautiful day out here in Bavaria. And an exciting one, where a new major update came to the website!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Fixed languages!</title><link href="/tum_info/2023/06/08/languages.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fixed languages!" /><published>2023-06-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-06-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/tum_info/2023/06/08/languages</id><content type="html" xml:base="/tum_info/2023/06/08/languages.html"><![CDATA[<p>Reporting for duty! Added a few more grade distributions from course exam statistics. But mainly fixed languages for language courses - in the past every exam was in English by default.</p>

<p>If you see that one of the courses you took is not on the website, please submit it! You can check out how on the <a href="https://mcmikecreations.github.io/tum_info/readme/">ReadMe page</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name>Mykola Morozov</name><email>mcmikecreations@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Reporting for duty! Added a few more grade distributions from course exam statistics. But mainly fixed languages for language courses - in the past every exam was in English by default.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Added modules!</title><link href="/tum_info/2023/05/16/modules.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Added modules!" /><published>2023-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/tum_info/2023/05/16/modules</id><content type="html" xml:base="/tum_info/2023/05/16/modules.html"><![CDATA[<p>Hey Twitter World! It’s Yours Truly. With the new update, the website now features a <a href="https://mcmikecreations.github.io/tum_info/modules/">Modules</a> section
with elective modules offered for different study programs. The data is fetched from the <a href="https://github.com/Vuenc/TUM-Master-Informatics-Offered-Lectures">repository by Vuenc</a>,
then gathered in one place and cross-linked with grade reports for your convenience. If you want to contribute something to the module pages
or can’t find your program on the page, go to their repository and <a href="https://github.com/Vuenc/TUM-Master-Informatics-Offered-Lectures/issues">file an issue</a>.</p>

<p>If you have any other ideas on what to put on the website, let me know!</p>]]></content><author><name>Mykola Morozov</name><email>mcmikecreations@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hey Twitter World! It’s Yours Truly. With the new update, the website now features a Modules section with elective modules offered for different study programs. The data is fetched from the repository by Vuenc, then gathered in one place and cross-linked with grade reports for your convenience. If you want to contribute something to the module pages or can’t find your program on the page, go to their repository and file an issue.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Improved scripts!</title><link href="/tum_info/2023/05/12/scripts.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Improved scripts!" /><published>2023-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/tum_info/2023/05/12/scripts</id><content type="html" xml:base="/tum_info/2023/05/12/scripts.html"><![CDATA[<p>Hi besties! I added a simpler way to contribute using the executable file (<a href="https://github.com/mcmikecreations/tum_info/releases/download/1.0.1/Grades.exe">Windows</a>, <a href="https://github.com/mcmikecreations/tum_info/releases/download/1.0.1/Grades">Linux</a>, <a href="https://github.com/mcmikecreations/tum_info/releases/download/1.0.1/Grades.dmg">MacOS</a>). You can find a video guide <a href="https://youtu.be/nHjuVhIJRaQ">here</a>. Now you can generate a file with all your grades and send it over Telegram or any other of the communication channels listed in the app! Also broke scripts down to improve reusability. Check <a href="https://mcmikecreations.github.io/tum_info/readme/">ReadMe</a> for more detailed instructions.</p>

<p>Special thanks to Selman for submitting their grades. We now have <strong>659 entries</strong>!</p>]]></content><author><name>Mykola Morozov</name><email>mcmikecreations@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hi besties! I added a simpler way to contribute using the executable file (Windows, Linux, MacOS). You can find a video guide here. Now you can generate a file with all your grades and send it over Telegram or any other of the communication channels listed in the app! Also broke scripts down to improve reusability. Check ReadMe for more detailed instructions.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">No more CDN!</title><link href="/tum_info/2023/05/03/cdn.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="No more CDN!" /><published>2023-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/tum_info/2023/05/03/cdn</id><content type="html" xml:base="/tum_info/2023/05/03/cdn.html"><![CDATA[<p>What is up, my fellow human beings!? This update of <a href="https://mcmikecreations.github.io/tum_info/courses/">the website</a> fixes an issue that has been nagging me for ages. You know how you open a course and the plot loads a bit later? That’s because I was using <a href="https://www.jsdelivr.com/package/npm/@observablehq/plot">a 3rd-party CDN hosting</a> for the js scripts that build the plot. Now I’ve made a copy (with proper copyright attribution) and store it with the other scripts on GitHub. The plots should show up faster and be easier to cache!</p>

<p>Separate thanks to Xavier and Vuenc for contributing their grade statistics. We now have <strong>652 entries</strong>!</p>]]></content><author><name>Mykola Morozov</name><email>mcmikecreations@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[What is up, my fellow human beings!? This update of the website fixes an issue that has been nagging me for ages. You know how you open a course and the plot loads a bit later? That’s because I was using a 3rd-party CDN hosting for the js scripts that build the plot. Now I’ve made a copy (with proper copyright attribution) and store it with the other scripts on GitHub. The plots should show up faster and be easier to cache!]]></summary></entry></feed>